[Music]
Ving when you can just you know critical
things
[Music]
right
dude all right y'all check this out so I
was just poking through the threat
Locker website trying to figure out what
of all the amazing features they have I
was going to talk to you about today and
the one I landed on was elevation
control okay check this out so threat
Locker has this feature that allows you
to decide what users can run what
programs at what permission level right
so if you've got a user a Dev maybe that
needs to run a specific program as local
admin you can allow just that program to
run as local admin you don't have to
give them a local admin account anymore
which greatly increases your attack
surface for an attacker um so this is a
great tool if people would use this I
think a lot less people would get MIM
cats and I think this would really
increase the security posture of the
organization all right cool so check it
out elevation control with threat locker
let's go back to the
show sup hackers it's time for the best
episode of the year the yearly rollup
episode where we look back on all of the
amazing moments across all 52 episodes
of
2024 um and we pick the best moments and
we conglomerate them into one big
episode now um that may sound like a
walk in the park but when you're
actually producing it it's pretty
freaking hard you have to go back and
listen to all of the 52 episodes from
this year you got to pick the best
moments from them and put them all
together um and that is a lot of work on
our production team on Richard on me um
on Christian and and so we actually
recruited some help from the community
this time um to get all that work done
and I just wanted to give them some
shout outs real quick for going back
listening to some of the episodes and
picking out the best moments for us to
review so those people are uh Mar flap
xss doctor mon syndrome impostor Beck
server inspector thoronet golden uh PJ
stew artc ins and wizar so thank you
guys so much for helping with that
really appreciate it I think we've got
some awesome segments coming up in this
episode um and I personally I really
enjoyed going back and kind of
reflecting on the year really shows uh
how much awesome content we've had on
ctbb and it was really hard to pick the
best SE ments um but these are the 10
best segments we we did cut it down a
little bit this year last year was a
three-hour episode um and we made it a
little bit shorter uh this time around
but uh hopefully we still grabbed the
best moments across all the episodes and
we're going to go ahead and do them in
inverse episode order so uh we're going
to start with the oldest ones and move
towards the newest ones uh and hope you
guys enjoyed as much as I did uh putting
it all together because uh We've really
had some great moments uh in 2024 so
thank you all the community for
continuing to support the podcast
continuing to make it possible via the
the Discord subs and everything um and
then also you know we are launching the
full-time Hunters Guild uh this past
week so if any of you guys are full-time
Hunters which I know many of you are um
then you're definitely going to want to
check that out cv. showt for full-time
um you're eligible if you are a
full-time Hunter AKA 50% or more of your
income comes from uh bug Bounty or if
you make over 100k a year doing it
part-time um and then you know you apply
and then here's one of the
misconceptions then we may approve or
not approve you because uh there are
some some people that do it 50% or more
of their time that have very little to
show for the results and we're trying to
build a really high quality Community
here um committed to accountability
keeping each other performant uh staying
on top of our goals um collaborating uh
and getting some help from our support
staff that we'll have uh dedicated to
this Guild so that's the kind of vision
for it apply if you're interested uh
we'll get you some more information okay
let's jump right into the uh cuts from
uh 2024 first one on the list is an
episode with uh with nhamc none other
than Ben himself um and he's dropping
some great tips on his blind xss
methodology and there's just some
there's just some great moments in this
one all right I think you guys will
enjoy it let's go um blind is just the
same as your regular stex say I want to
say a long time is scored more than
reflected but the difference is instead
of it happening on the front app that
you see it happens on the back back end
where the company's uh Team sees it so
think about you know if hacker one had a
back portal for example where they can
see a reports you have cost scripting
payLo that doesn't you know fire in the
report section but it fires in hacko
ones back and funny enough if you look
up I actually had that happened to
hacker one once no way I was working
there oh my go icess fired off an
internal Network at hacker one uh but
yeah it's just a lot of it is uh you
just learn that these companies make
mistakes they the Mist don't happen in
the front end a lot of times it happens
in the back end because they go well no
one's going to ever see this and we
don't have to worry about it and guess
what it does happen a lot more than you
can expect and and so I I that exact
rationale was what I wanted to talk to
you about how do you
identify what pieces of information are
going to end up in an admin panel
somewhere you know where where do you
get those
ideas uh I think it's very I want to say
it's I don't want to say it's common
sense but it's just very like it's a
thing that you think a company wants to
collect on you right yeah so when
register what matters so that you that's
your name your email address your
address uh your credit card information
in some cases anything that could
identify you as a duplicate account for
example like they could say these are
the same user so that could be your
browser information for example and
things like that and then things that
could also traces you like when you have
different websites and things like that
right it's how do they identify you as a
user and you as a browser or um you know
not the user itself but like the the
the browser for example or the the
device we say the device for so those
are the things that I look at right
those are the things that I always
assume companies are collecting on you
but then also it goes the information
that you put in to the company so let's
talk about um let's say like Spotify for
example you guys post your podcast on
there the description the the guest the
name of the you know you guys and those
are also they collect but they could you
know people probably find those EX early
on days on those programs but they don't
think about like oh I wonder if this
fires here is it going to also fire in
the back end and if it does how do I get
them to fire on that back end right
those are the things that you have to
figure out you have to assume how do I
go from A to B your a is I have EXs on
the core app how do I get to fire on the
back end how do I get this engineer the
support person without social
engineering naturally go click on it
okay so that's that's where I was going
next with that was like okay so we've
got information we put in we're using a
blind xss payload that we can get a call
back from how do we how are we going to
be the one user that the support agent
clicks on or the you know backend
analytics admin clicks on I'm laugh
think as I I don't know how to say this
I don't want tell me I know I know what
you're gonna say here what Joel what do
you think I'm gonna say I want to see
what you you think we can cut this out
if we need to you just you open a
support chat and you say hey I'm having
having an issue with this thing and
click that that is that is that is also
that's a very good approach but no the I
I don't want to promote committing fraud
I want to start with that yeah but fraud
detection is a big part of
Technology how do you get what's the
easiest way to get banned on a
platform right what's the easiest way
what is the easiest way for them to be
like holy crap who is this guy what do
we do what do we do to get rid of this
person right that is the number one step
it's uh either fraud or too much traffic
things like hey look at me like
screaming like ban me number one step is
get banned like that's the first step
like how do I get him to go ban me right
this could be me reporting my own
account with like 20 other accounts for
example oh my gosh I just do that right
yeah so what Joel said is it's it's so
first of all please don't go and hassle
support people please don't do that to
be real but listen but there's a
difference between saying hey I have a
problem it's a legitimate problem that
causes an issue versus going like hey
click on this thing I've never asking a
support so have to click on the link but
I am using the site like an actual like
user and I go hey I can't find this
information where do I find it and I go
oh I still can't find it I really can't
sometimes because guess what my page is
broken like I have a script tag in
that's broken I'm not lying to them so I
asked I'm like hey could you set that
information for me that's it's a
lightweight social engineering but I try
to avoid as as much as I can a lot of
times a lot of this blind ACC that I'm
getting nowadays isn't the support staff
being included it's me figuring out
these companies how their processes work
and what does it happen to get them to
look into something I do whether it's
like you know I put my credit card
number in there but the last digit is
wrong A lot of times with um when you
order something online for example they
process that manually they check for
your order manually sometimes especially
for your band user that's one of the
biggest things dude the number one thing
I used to do a couple years ago was
every single time uh John bini and I
were sitting at um in a hotel one day
I I love I love John I look at him I go
John you want to make a thousand bucks
today he goes what do you mean I go
let's make an order on this side and he
goes what do you mean I'm like I'm
banned but I bet you if you put this on
this website with a blind cont scripting
in the address the second address line I
promise we're going to get cross te when
we wake up tomorrow he looks at me he
goes bet we do it the next morning we
wake up sure enough it fires no way fast
forward fast forward to five years later
this is this quarter this last quarter I
call him again and I go John do you want
to make some money buddy he's like what
do you got this time Ben and I go like
you have an account on this particular
set that I want to use I'm banned can
you just go and do this goes well I have
a problem with my account I'm like
perfect that's even better can you try
this sure enough tries it another BL
starts off it's just getting an
understanding of how these companies
work what requires them to manually have
someone click on your page and then you
assuming this is the information they
going to see about I'm I'm wondering is
is there any Merit to sending your your
CR like say it's like uh some sort of
logging endpoint or something like that
is there any Merit to sending it on
a uh like a Time based basis okay like
every five minutes we're going to send
another one through um and and because
whenever somebody first opens up the
admin portal you know there's always
going to be like sort of like a page
imaginated list or something like that
and if you land in that first you know
25 or whatever then you might get in
that in that front area have you ever
thought about that or any tried anything
like that I haven't done it on purpose
because when you do stuff in the kattin
manner it's a little bit spammy and it
is the last thing I want is but I've had
that happen a couple of times a couple
of like fun ones is um it asks you for
like a note sometimes I put in the note
it doesn't fire it doesn't even fire on
their backand they copy my note into an
internal n into internal app for track
and then it fires right I've seen that
happen before um the typical like in my
email was a fun one one of a really cool
one was a
website um my password was a blind cost
payload no it was
not that fired this is just me copy
pasting the same thing for my name you
know email everything and then the the
password was clear texttext clear text
no way
that's ridiculous
man that one hasn't happened this was
like eight nine years ago this was like
no yeah uh
2015 2016 so six seven years ago it
happened um it's just it's just you know
you never know right you never know
there there's a couple of times where
it's fired off in a um engineer's like
local machine because they downloaded
everybody's feedback and they were
parsing it that's crazy that's so cool
and and so with that I kind of want to
ask how do you track where your payload
Source was because what what always
happens to me when I do blind xss is all
is I'll Ty you know throw this payload
in there and then I'll get a call back
and then I'm like [__] where did I put
that in a form somewhere you know and
how let me ask you a
question what are you doing for tracking
what are you using a cost are you using
like a xss hunter yeah I'm just using
xss Hunter normal xss Hunter question
number two
if you give it oh okay that's why well I
don't know how that works um I don't
know if truffle allows you do this can
you give it a
path what what do you oh yeah like a
specific path at the end oh get your own
path you only get one path yeah oh so
see this is what I do I have my own
domain yeah uh if you go to the London
event it was spammed everywhere I think
people like trolling me at some point um
so I start deleting it but I have a
domain that is not a it's a it's a ciz
it's a xss hunter um JavaScript without
the back end of Xs this Hunter so it's
just a JavaScript that they have yeah um
and it it just hooks into a PHP file and
that PHP file is what processes the
entire like when it fires right that's
the back end is a PHP file that's like
garbage it's actually written by Chad
gbt I [__] you not oh my gosh the the
front end of it I have a HTT access Rule
and a in there that catches every single
path you give and it serves that
Javascript file if it it's not valid so
my 404 is that JS file that pops up so
when I do a cost you know when I do a
blindex asss I do
domain.com whatever I want to make a
note of so the note could be first name
in profile that's an invalid path so
when it fires it fires with uh my Js
file and it shows me where it's at but a
lot of times it's also easy to track
because you know it's something like
your name or you know your password and
things like that it's obvious uh
feedback ones are always the hardest one
to track but a lot of companies don't
care where it came from because they
know where it came from yeah right they
they know where they came from that's
that's really crazy I mean I can't
imagine in scenarios where developers
are like copy and pasting your data into
different applications or something like
that how you trace it back to the source
it has to be done on the company side I
imagine that one was a hard one because
um yeah there was some issues with that
be like oh will you messag RT I'm like
no I didn't message anybody they copy
pasted this dude and I'm like I did not
you know stus to them and it turned out
it was a note that I left they copied
the note into the internal app and then
fired wow that that's that's crazy man
what a what a crazy hacking story yeah I
know I know your ex has Hunter instance
because I know Mr Sam cury likes to use
it and uh I have my that's not mine
that's not mine that's not mine the only
person that uses mine no I think that's
uh X that's not mine that's X's I also
use that must be using your script cuz I
was looking through it and there's like
a bunch of like naham references in the
JS it could be it could be that uh
they're using a version of it I shared
that with everybody in you guys' group
like I have no problem using it because
it's not something I wrote It's also
like I also saw Sean using in a specific
way I Incorporated in mine but the
biggest thing that I have is the the PHP
file in the back end and
uh me and Z have a um I can't actually
say the name of a bot I'll send you guys
the name of the bot later but we have a
bot that we've I almost H the name it
could have got me a lot of trouble
but uh we it's the the name of the bot
is the name of the CEO of the company
okay
okay so we have
a we have a and then the their team has
also seen this bot when I screenshot it
for them but that's so funny uh we have
a we have a bot that um it just says
like hey everyone on on Discord it's out
everyone new blind C scripting and it
gets the URL from that report and then
also links to the report that I have
it's a Tex SP I store all on my server
it's password protected you know we have
to have a credentials to log into it and
I just go look at it and then analyze it
and things like that that system is one
of the most [__] up addicting things
I've ever done because when I was
getting a lot of BL scripting suit I was
waking up at 5:00 a.m. rolling over and
looking at my phone to see if a new one
popped up and then when you see it
popped and you can't go back to sleep
yeah it's the same thing yeah dude I
just set up my ownx as S Hunter and um I
saw how
was set up cuz I thought it was like
standard and I really I really like it
cuz I'm going to set up something to do
the same thing with like the path catch
all and the subdomain catch
all man Ben rocking it as always okay
this next episode is from episode 59
entitled bug Bounty Gadget hunting and
hackers intuition and personally this
was my favorite episode of the year just
sitting down with Joel talking through
all of these bug Bounty gadgets that we
have and how to sort of duct tape them
all together was a blast so if I had to
one episode uh you know maybe toting my
own horn a little bit here since this is
a Justin and Joel episode but um this
episode I think has a lot of really good
takeaways in it um and we did cut a
segment for you uh it is specifically is
talking about um HTML injection uh image
injection in particular um and then
moving into uh open redirect client side
path traversal and uh client Side open
redirect which is a little bit of a
weird bug so I think you guys will enjoy
it check out this segment I think about
one of my favorite vs and I think I've
talked about this on the Pod before but
I'll mention it again and this was an
image injection okay um and this is not
even like I wasn't breaking out of any
context and we'll kind of talk about
context breaks a little bit later as as
a gadget in and of themselves but um if
you're able to inject into the source
attribute of an image there's some weird
stuff you can do um and and especially
if you can do it in a targeted way for
example there was a scenario much like
the dingling markup example that I I
gave just a second ago where I was able
to do a stored image injection on
somebody essentially within an
application okay and I could force the
browser to load up a specific image and
then what I did is I forced them to hit
the log out
endpoint with the image the image tag
yeah yeah so essentially I would send
them a message um and then that message
would get pushed to their you know
dashboard or whatever and that dashboard
would have an image and then as soon as
they log into their dashboard it would
load that image and log them out and
then as soon as they tried to do
anything on the application it would get
it would they'd get logged out and then
to REO and then when they REO they would
go back to the dashboard page and you
know and so there there's a couple ways
that you can exploit this I actually
exploited it again recently in a
scenario where there wasn't a log out SE
surf but there was a log in SE surf so
so you can uh you could essentially
repeatedly log them into a different
account and then they could never get
access to their own account W okay so it
it's it's it's sort of a tricky exploit
for sure um but image injection and then
I know there used to be like like 401
injection or something like that I don't
know if that works in any browsers we
kind of we we keep on talking about that
and then we still don't know um but I
know some at one point people were using
401 injection on an image in image
source uh and that would pop up a an off
box that would allow you to exfiltrate
off um under a different sites domain in
fact our friend Mr Sam Curry has and it
has a disclosed report on Twitter from
2017 oh my gosh Sam what have you done
Mark as a low marked as a
low that uh is exactly this HTM HTTP 401
response injection hey guys real quick I
want to remind you about the critical
thinking Discord Community there's been
a ton of great activity on the chats
lately people just kind of shooting the
breeze to drop in New hacking tips and
advice uh sharing cool research that
sort of thing uh so it's definitely
something you're going to want to get in
on if you haven't already also we've got
the subscriber tiers in place now which
will give you access to really cool
things like Master Class AMA uh just
random scripts that I drop it's kind of
like our Inner Circle um so if you want
to get in on that please do we would
really appreciate it also it helps
support the show so if you're interested
in any of that head over to cb. show
Discord to join the community today and
we'll see you over there all right back
to the
show I don't know there are some edge
cases in which this might work in mobile
browsers or in like Firefox or something
like that so if if you're really really
grasping for straws you know in a live
hacking event and you're like I got to
find something here you know then it
might be might be worth a report it
might land you a low but um definitely
the stuff with the targeted image
injection I mean to be honest that can
get you into a
high because if you can literally just
Doss the whole app for a targeted user
that's availability High um yeah I mean
I feel like that's that's impact right
there if you can figure out some way to
to to demonstrate that then then there
you go right
um so speaking of uh des desperateness
and uh you know if you're really
desperate report this uh open redirects
let's talk about open redirects because
okay as from the program side I see this
a lot actually um where people report
open redirects with no impact and um
what do you think about I I could not
recommend against it any any stronger
like like don't do that wow that's
that's a strong position like I really I
think open redirects are like one of the
lamest bug classes by itself and like
there really is like no impact in
today's day and age right like like just
by itself like I can send you to a link
you go to another Link at best
fishing like yeah I it's it's a very
very hard use case um an exploitation
case I find but what you can do with
that there are a ton of things right um
couple great examples s FS a lot of
times there'll be either a filter on the
URL that's being that you're being sent
to or that's being requested to that
needs to be within a certain host name
or within a certain IP range um you can
use that as a redirect to go to you know
AWS metadata or something yeah um we we
we've seen that you know that that
technique has been around forever and
stuff like that so that that's
definitely a tried and true use case for
open redirects the ones that I'm I'm
more interested in nowadays are the ooth
path traversals essentially you being
able to
leak an oath token via open redirect and
the the ones that I I think are actually
more interesting are uh client side path
reversals and or iframe injections
essentially uh iframe Source injections
so you know if you can if you can
provide a a place where you're supposed
to be able to embed any page on uh on a
specific website in an application then
you can use an an open redirect in that
in that environment to get your own page
embedded in there um that's that's a
scenario that once again is a gadget
that can that can expose a lot of um
helpful things like post message
listeners um you know in in Mobile's
case you know sometimes you can get use
it for like um like JavaScript what are
they called JavaScript Bridges or
something like that Joel y yeah yep
JavaScript interfaces in in a web view
um yeah so just you know accessing
specific functions or or um parameters
on the window object to interact with
the actual application um really cool
purposes there and dude this is the one
that just like lately has been just so
so cool to see work we talk about CLI
side Pat virials all the time and client
side path traversals are kind of a
gadget of themselves um but this is a
great example where you can put two
gadgets together to make a vault right
so let's say you've got a client side
path reversal so essentially what what
that means is you're able to control
um either the the the place to which a
fetch request is sent or like maybe even
aname that's embedded dynamically using
JavaScript or something like that
um uh but normally the fetch scenario is
is where it's at and you're able to
inject into that URL scheme and Traverse
and then hit an open redirect so I saw
somebody at the live hacking event do
this yeah and and I also my mentee
sitting right there at that at that desk
behind me found one the other day and
fully exploited it and I was just like
dude this bug is like so clutch um and
so I really love to see it used with the
client side patch reversal where you
Traverse hit the open redirect fetch
automatically follows redirects um which
I don't know I won't go down the path of
of whining about that uh bug that I
found recently where I I couldn't
actually exploit it because fetch autof
follows redirects and you can't even
read the redirect location ever um but
uh but seeing that actually work out in
a client side patrial environment is
amazing and it's so often works out to
be xss even in like heavily sanitized
environments because they're not
expecting malicious input to come back
from a fetch request that they sent to
their own API right right so there's
pretty much no way to to you know
properly anticipate that um so that's a
really cool use case for prir yeah I
mean there's so much protection and
advice on the server side with srf right
where it's like okay never take a user
control parameter and and make a request
to it and all this stuff but then like
so much of that falls to the Wayside on
the client side because it's just not
the same thought process and there's so
much different development around like
you know it seems very harmless right
you're like oh I'm just getting a query
parameter or something and but that
that's all it takes you know that that's
just putting it in the fetch request and
because of that behavior and the
ubiquity of um you know open redirects
and all that kind of stuff it just makes
it such a
larger problem and with all these single
page applications nowadays it's you know
even more so right um so so yeah really
really interesting stuff there yeah so I
don't know about what you said about the
open redirect I think open redirect is
right on the line of like if a company
is really taking security seriously they
want to clean that up because it can be
used in so many scenarios right um but
don't be surprised if it's a low like
face value never more if you report it
like they're just going to be like okay
I guess we'll fix this but
like for sure yeah um and in that
scenario do really rarely you report
that because it's it's uh much more high
value to be able to use it in a chain
even if it's not present rather than
excuse me man water this morning um
rather than chaining it into something
that's you know much higher value down
the line yeah so and I will say I think
it probably every single live hacking
event at least once I see in the collab
Channel somebody go hey does anybody
have an open redirect on open redirect
yeah 100% and you're like ah okay yeah
this is still a thing this is still
kicking so um definitely check that out
you know what's interesting about that
too is for all the people there that
don't need an open redirect but might
have an open redirect like that should
be inspiration for you right because
somebody needs an open rir which means
the open rir that you have somewhere
there is a use case for that you know
and you just got to go find it and the
fact that that happens every single live
hacking event really sort of lends
itself to the scenario of like oh I have
an open redir but I can't really find
anything to do with it well that's
definitely out there you know somebody's
there is definitely some
placees exactly exactly so that that
should be inspiration for any of you
that uh either need an open redirect or
or don't need an open redirect and
should an open redirect um yeah
absolutely uh so sort of tangental
Gadget to that is the client Side open
redirect and this one I actually think
is
garbage and I actually was there's a
pretty serious differentiation between
client side redirect open redirect and
uh server side open redirect right
um depending on the scenario you know
you still May able to use it the pretty
much the only use I could come up with
is iframe uh iframe Source injection
essentially like there's pretty much
nothing else you can really do with it
if you're doing like a window location.
hre and you cannot do the JavaScript
scheme then
you're I mean you're you're pretty much
screwed it doesn't it doesn't leak the
hash it doesn't leak any of the quer
parameters it just goes to the location
that you define with the input that you
inputed um and so I don't know maybe I'm
missing something there and I'd be
interested if anyone in the community
can point me in the direction of
something that uh I might be able to do
with this besides you know injecting
into an iframe but that's pretty much
the only thing I could come up with yeah
I'm trying to think if there's anything
creative probably the best scenario I
can come up with is like maybe on mobile
depending on the permissions within a
web view you could redirect to a file or
something like that um and then you know
pivot from there depending on but but
that's going to be very situation
specific um yeah so yeah I mean it's one
of those things that as a G again as a
gadget like it potentially has use cases
but they're very very narrow especially
even for the ones that we've been
talking about like client Side open
redirect is is really like you know one
in a 100 type barely barely ever use but
but it's there and have it in the back
of your mind you know what is not not a
vulnerability but and is not really even
a gadget but kind of feels like one is
uh post message open redirect and I've
I've kind of run into this scenario a
lot where it's like okay I'm really
close to X because if I could just send
this post message to redirect the page
to a JavaScript URI then I'd have xss
but you can't use the JavaScript URI
because of some you know very tough to
bypass sanitization or something but you
can redirect the URL to an arbitrary
host yeah but it's it's useless because
essentially you unless it's in an if
frame I guess is the only scenario that
that would actually be useful and then
you could say like you know window. open
X is is the new window right and then
dot frames one and then send the post
message to that or whatever and have it
redirect inside the trusted page then
it's a little bit useful but um you can
always just redirect the other tab that
you've opened up anyway with window.
open so you just do you know x equals
window. open and then x. location equals
XYZ and then you've redirect to the page
to that location or name the windows
yeah yeah exactly and so um that didn't
make the list this time around uh on the
on the gadget side but is an honorable
mention uh and also something that I
would kind of be interested to see if
anyone
like knows any way that that could be
helpful maybe the only thing that I
could think of is like ah it could maybe
be helpful in like a same sight strict
scenario right where like you can't even
do top level navigations to send the
cookies you've got to actually come from
a specific origin and yeah if you could
trigger the redirect
from the origin then you could
trigger get based SE surf on a same
sight strict scenario
[Music]
yeah I mean and again right it's like
one of those really like stretch
scenarios that's going to be super super
specific to you know yeah I don't know
I'm trying to think if there's anything
and I keep falling back to like these
more like native scenarios where like an
electron app or like something that has
more schemes or like stuff that you know
you stuff other than JavaScript and
other than HTML or sorry HTP htps um
that maybe you could you could exploit
in some creative way but uh yeah I don't
know it's it's very very
tricky see see what I'm saying that was
pretty good right that was a good
segment I I want to I want to put out
more content like that where we're
really breaking down um you know
technical gadgets components and showing
innovative ways to duct tape them all
together all right cool so this next
segment is actually going to be from Sam
Curry this is episode 65 motivation and
methodology with Sam Curry um you know I
don't even have to tell you about Sam
Curry Sam Curry is a freaking Legend um
he he has some of the most amazing hacks
I've ever seen very unique hacker um and
in this segment he comes on the Pod and
talks about the vulnerability class that
he coined secondary context path
reversals um which I was just working on
one a couple days ago very common
vulnerability um exploiting it takes a
lot of expertise and Sam kind of gives
us some thoughts on how to do that um
utilizing both hacker intuition and sort
of Hands-On methodology so let's jump to
that
clip so Sam you have so much research
online so many stories um so many cool
things that uh we need to unpack here
but one of the things you are most well
known for is secondary context bucks um
I don't know did you like my first
exposure to secondary context was you uh
did you did you coin that term same I
did yeah B
funny I appr yeah it's funny seeing that
term like used I'm like oh my God
someone's actually using that word I
just put those two things together
that's like a title that's clutch man
but it it I mean obviously I'm sure some
OG you know on some blog back in like
you know 28 well you know 2028 208 28
2008 yeah the future no um you know way
back wrote something about it but you
know that blog or that talk that you did
on secondary context stuff was my first
exposure to that um and and I think it
it really made it more uh WI recognized
in the industry um and we have a cool
cool bug we can talk about that with the
Starbucks bug um and that's on Sim c.net
as well uh that you guys can go read
about but talk to me about when you
started realizing secondary context bugs
were a thing and how you started working
through that whole
concept right yeah so my initial
exposure to like secondary context bugs
was on uh Yahoo's Luminate which was
like Yahoo's small business platform for
like deploying websites and stuff and
what I realized was that uh I originally
thought it was like path like file path
traversal right because I was like able
to Traverse and like add directories and
I'd been spending so long in this one
app and I was just like getting and I
eventually started testing for it and
I'm like oh my God there's file path Ral
and even in it's funny too because I
blogged about it and even in the blog
post I refer to it as like I remember
this local I remember this so this was
not a file path
traversal it was not yeah it was
actually HB pth reversal but even at the
time like I'm I guess the S password
file just didn't exist and it's like no
that's just not that's not what was
happening um so with that kind of
exposure to it uh I started looking for
similar stuff in more and more places
and I eventually realized that like the
internet was slowly being built towards
this like interesting like Network model
where like oh you want to serve a CDN
from like dubdub dub. yahoo.com where
like you want to serve images but you
don't have to like you've got this very
complicated configuration of like proxy
rules and different passes so maybe that
you know slash images instead of being
like a folder on like one box because of
like load Bal how crazy that would be if
it was just all served from the same box
now the SL Imes route is being proxy to
like some internal server for a CDN
right that's interesting do you think
this is a function of needing to do load
balancing more
effectively I think it's a mix of things
right I think that um if you're a team
who you have like you know maybe a
static blog but at the same time like
you have
authentication functionality on your
setic blog and the team who deploys you
know you've got like devops team one
devops team two and then like you have
to kind of merge them together sometimes
the easiest way to like differentiate
routes and folders and things I think is
by adding that reverse proxy and then
separating the services into two um so
yeah that's probably the biggest thing
that I've seen from like the engineering
side is it's the service like that
service aspect a lot of people don't
think about this because they're not in
in engineering or but for engineering
orgs like split up functionality into
Services right and services are
separately deployed and in order for
these things to interact with each other
instead of having just one giant
application that's handling everything
from one place that can interact
internally with everything itself it has
to make some sort of call whether that's
like grpc or Kafka or whatever like and
a lot of times it's just HTTP they build
an HTTP client like for that service
that just like calls internal endpoints
on that other service on you know their
internal Network and it passes data back
and forth and it's a lot you know it's a
lot more simple than people would think
where they're like oh like you know they
must have they they're load balancing
it's like no they there's two separate
services and they have to talk to each
other somehow and they just did that
with an HTP request and they did it
really really quickly and effectively in
a in an insecure way and that's where
things are starting to fall apart right
yeah exactly and like even uh external
Services too like apis like maybe you've
got a Maps plugin like you want to serve
that data and you pass in a path that
goes like Google Maps API and like it's
very very interesting how like
complicated it goes I think one of the
reasons like this kind of research kind
of came about there's different people
who had worked on like similar things in
the past there's really excellent blog
post like France Rosen um he he he
should have been like he should be the
originator um his work with like Matias
and others like I think probably even a
few years before that talk and I even
messaged him when I gave a talk I said
like I feel like this is similar to a
lot of work that you've done in the past
and I was like if there's anything here
like I'm G I'm making sure to credit you
for a lot of this um I want to make sure
I'm not like stepping on your toes a
little bit but uh I wanted to say like
the the way
that the way that totally lost my TR
thought but maybe I can maybe I can
redirect you that that's fine the the so
as you're starting to develop this this
understanding of modern web architecture
where these reverse proxies are are in
place like that um
and the tricky part for me still lies in
where does the authentication live
because there's there's a lot of there's
a lot of uh secondary context pth to
vers all over the place but the backend
server is also using oth and it's just
like okay well I can hit a different
endpoint you know and sometimes you can
do weird stuff with that like like sea
surfs or like um you know some sort of
um method confusion
and that sort of thing but
uh the majority of the time that
understanding that off piece is really
is really pivotal
right right yeah 100% I mean the off
component is so important to everything
because like if you're a like a lot of
structures for instance uh we saw this a
lot in the car hacking where uh as an
example like you have serus xam at the
top where there's all these different
vehicle Brands beneath it like Ford you
know whatever but the serus XM Service
is like the authenticated one so each of
those car car companies has like an API
key that they use globally so it's like
once you if you can leak that key you
change the context between like one user
with access to one thing and then like
you leak the key and then you can talk
to that service access to that back end
service yeah exactly right so one
example there is like you know maybe
you're fuzzing for you know secondary
contact stuff and you throw in like a
new line character for a URI parameter
instead of like your account ID maybe
you do one two three% z d and then you
get a stack Trace back where it's like
the API call to internal. company.com
question mark API key equals and you're
like aha I see the API key you take that
and then you're like hey team this is
allowing me to access anybody's stuff so
you give them right but like you said
the authent the yeah it's this sounds
like a very real
examp maybe yeah maybe maybe it is but
uh you know doing some uh hacking on the
program recently I don't know if you can
disclose their bugs but there's a lot of
similar stuff like there right with the
with the secondary contact
stuff yeah it's like a yeah there's tons
of uh a lot of the for instance like a
lot of people hunt for actuators like
really heavily and like when you start
exploring like actuator secondary
contact stuff it's really fun because
it's like you know in some Javascript
file somewhere there's like this route
which is reverse proxy maybe it's like
API gw- you know internal slash or
something then you hit that route and
then that's where you your actuator ends
or like dot do semicolon actuator ends
and then like it lets you kind of hunt
more thoroughly I guess in this scenario
you're hitting Dev API API Dev endpoints
using this this um secondary context
sort of path traversal so going through
the front end then traversing on the
back end hitting these actuator end
points which wouldn't be exposed
publicly because of probably path
limitations um through the reverse proxy
and and then like are you normally
hunting for things where it's going to
dump the full response back to you
without any modification or are you you
going to try to hit these things blind
because a lot of times there's a parsing
of the response from that backend API
and then that that kind of hex up your
your visibility into the back end
right right yeah the having a response
is beautiful it makes you so happy when
you see that HP response leaked back to
you you feel amazing but a lot of times
it is blind right and I was with another
for Nathaniel it really is um it's like
a I would say too like to finish that
bit like a Nathan lmer donut um I was
with him on a trip and I like stor into
his hotel room like manically with my
laptop I'm like if I do ABC it doesn't
do anything but if I
doxyz it does this thing but like I
can't reproduce it on this one and like
he he's looking at me I've sat there for
six hours trying to figure it out and
he's like this guy like what is he
talking about like it's absurd but
because there are so many conditionals
that relate to like the uh you know like
you're trying to explain to your friend
you're like if I do a pound sign does
this behavior and if I do an Amper
standand it's this behavior and like you
have to like really build out this like
brain map for each individual case right
I think the most complicated like
secondary context bug I had was like
this stored uh you would add a value to
a database with like an an sign and like
change the you change the format from
XML to Json yeah yeah and then like on
another endpoint You' call it and it'
get retrieved it like and it was how you
identify so it's like a stored secondary
cont I've never even thought about a
stored secondary
context yeah logically a lot of times uh
it can
be some things I think you can look for
there if it's like external services
like a external apis that you know for
instance uh you know are they leveraging
some third party API that has an API key
or like is there one you've already
identified that's like you can kind of
add on to
um but they're so Case by case right
like one service has like one behavior
and you you have to build those mind
maps I guess yeah it it when you're
talking about the external Services it
makes me it reminds me of the Starbucks
bug and just to give a a quick overview
of this um like essentially what in this
scenario we actually had access to the
full response right that was coming back
and and we were able to on that one we
were able to path Traverse back on on
this Starbucks AP
and hit it was it was a third party
right it was Microsoft was it
graph yeah it was a Microsoft Graph
Search I think it was like a they had
like a I don't know if it was a third
party service or was a utility they had
but it was connected to their core their
their core Starbucks 100 million user
Records Was it was connected to and so
essentially like we we were working on
this together and what amazed me when we
were working on this together was one
that that you identified one that leaked
the full response which allowed us to
get so much more interesting data back
but
um uh but for two you were able to
bruteforce these paths along the way and
I just I don't know man I don't know
maybe it's just because I don't do a lot
of brute forcing as a part of my
methodology but it's just that's just
some and fron fron does it even weirder
I mean fron Brute Forces it as well but
fron also just has like this sick sense
of like you know what I bet customer is
before this and and it's like and then
he'll guess because we we were working
on this Target and it was like and it
was we weren't allowed to bre Force they
said explicitly literally no Brute Force
please do not brute force it okay and so
we're like we need to bruteforce it
because how are we going to figure out
the paths you know that we're traversing
and Fran's just guessed four pads
deep and I'm like so good you've got to
be kidding me man um so I guess for this
in your experience with the brute
forcing what is your approach to that
what word list using are you generating
custom things you know is it just
something I've got to start doing that
I'm not
doing yeah I mean a really a really
simple list that I like to use um it's
in burp by default but it's like serers
side variable names and it's just like
heard you know path parameter yeah exil
Mike Robert showed me this like he uses
it from time to time for like parameters
and stuff but I think if you go to the
simple list it's like servide variable
names but uh the thought process for
trying to Brute Force the past or guess
the paths is like one it lets you
confirm that like you're not just
traversing to like the same request
you're on because a lot of the times
what will happen is like you think
you're traversing but in reality it's
like a normal fied like API request
where it's been condensed down to the
normal request so you're actually just
calling
yourself but yeah it's very you're like
oh I'm just you know you like spam
someone about and you're like delete our
messages you're like never mind ignore
me um but the uh but brute forcing a
path is really fun because like you know
you can kind of guess like friend and if
it's fronze mispronounce his name for 10
years you know so I apologize um but he
he doing a customer like makes a lot of
sense where you can kind of guess the
format is like V1 you know V2 V3
whatever but building it out um I wish
there was more General tips but it
really is caseby case basis you know are
they using camel case up lower case
upper are they separating are you
looking at the front end a like paths
for that to to determine that
information or you because I guess at
some point it's getting proxy back
through so maybe they're using similar
name conventions on the back end as
well yeah that that's one thing that uh
you can kind of pick up on is like on
the front end if they refer to your
account as like accountor ID or
something like that you know those
variable names that are like normal you
can kind of like interplace those
um most of the time I'll just send it
through if there's no rate limiting I
have like a massive word list that chubs
gave me that is like
500,000 good they're really good
yeah all right all right next up is
Johan Carlson three Monon check-in on
fulltime bug Bounty that's episode 69 um
and we took a snippet in this one
talking specifically about highly cspd
environments and how Johan was I don't
know what's that quote from like Bane
like I was born in the darkness you know
Johan was born in the highly CSP
enironment um and so he has some really
great takeaways about how to survive in
that in that environment um specifically
by the use of script gadgets and how um
various pieces of code can be monitoring
the Dom for uh various um patterns you
know query selectors that sort of thing
of things being added to the Dom which
may even make it past um uh Dom purify
or something of the like uh and then how
to utilize and chain those gadgets
together uh to create an exploit in
those highly cspd environments so
definitely a good one check this one out
and the the other thing that I wanted to
kind of bring up and highlight here is
this whole concept so we talk about
gadgets on the Pod a lot right um one of
the things that we haven't talked about
quite as much is this whole concept of a
script script Gadget within the page in
these high CSP environments how can we
convert um you know HTML injection into
something a little bit more functional
using these pieces of of script uh that
already exist on the page so um it's
reading through a couple of your other
pieces of of work and this as well it
it's become clear to me that um this is
one of your your this is your jam and
this is in my mind you're you're one of
the most foremost experts on the
specific sort of Gadget of sorts um so I
want you to give us a little bit of
insight into um how exactly this how you
discover these um sort of events and
obviously you can look at like hash
changes and stuff like that so anytime
we're trying to exploit anything in
these sort of environments it's always
great to like go to Global listeners
open your Dev tool go to Global
listeners look at the hash change event
and kind of see what what code is going
to be running on hash change but looking
at the the write up you passed along to
me as well there's like you know there
are events happening when there's a
specific uh class uh of object being
added to the Dom and like sorts of
things like that that are just way out
there so how are you finding these in
the first place in order to construct
this like beautiful
chain it's a I think probably it's quite
funny because when I started like I was
looking into so when I did my thesis way
back the the gitlab thing yeah uh we
were one of the things that we did then
was that we downloaded like all the
disclosed reports from gitlab uh into a
spreadsheet me and my thesis partner uh
so when we started we we read like and
at that time I didn't know anything
about this like uh security or like uh
but we read like all of these reports
like one after another uh and some
things stood out and you sort of
realized that at that time at least like
William wax he was like the the main
antagonist on gitlab like he was
crushing it with RC and stuff at that
time on like xsss and so I just studied
his works and classic
highly recommend that to anyone who has
the time yeah so mimic is the sincerest
form of flattery right true yeah and
where from where I was coming from I was
like okay so this is how you do it like
you have to find these gadgets and you
have to do all of this and like because
I was starting I found my first uh cross
side scripting like by super accident
just after um I had been doing this
research like the the thesis paper for
three months uh like trying putting
payloads every and stuff like that
didn't find anything and then the summer
came and I was done with school and
everything and I had passed and
everything was fine and I just got this
uh like feeling I was at my parents uh
like having some summer vacation and I
just thought like okay I'm going just go
in and try this I had this one injection
point that I I wanted to do something
you could name like a default repository
uh thing when some when someone creates
a project and it's it shows you some
instru instructions like run these
commands to create an empty repository
whatever uh and I know that I you could
put something in there and I just went
there and just added a super basic like
script alert thing and then it popped
and I was like what I mean I was like
can't be this easy no no no it can't be
that easy and also like I I know that I
tested this like just a couple of weeks
back and after all of this happened and
later I I looked and the code change was
just like two weeks old
so it was like super just like by this
accident that I went there like and they
actually changed the code between me
first testing it and then testing it
again wow that's wild it's crazy but and
then I I stumbled so that popped on my
local thing and then I went to
gitlab.com and I was like yeah I'm going
to get this like super awesome high
paying bug now and nothing happened and
that was my first encounter with the CSP
like I I had never heard about it before
I just conso said like CSP blocked I was
like
what from that day on Johan was
triggered anytime he saw a
CSP yeah so no but and then I went and
just U so and so some people had already
used some of these gadgets before on
gitlab uh and then uh I found some of my
own as well just by essentially like
reading the source code and like
gripping for these kinds of behaviors
where it's like looking
for I I kind of went from the sync like
I found places where it did like fetch
requests I have a few reports where I
can do like these client side uh attacks
where I could create some element and it
will be replaced by some form that I can
control the path and then I can just
make like one put request to the API but
with that one request you can make
yourself an admin if it's like an admin
who clicks the so it it seems to me just
from hearing that explanation and
looking at your you know hacker one
history and and that sort of thing that
you're you're just this is a function of
you being sort of growing as a hacker in
a highly cspd environment because I
think most people don't start off at
gitlab and and don't start off at you
know some of these other more hardened
targets that have these CPS in place so
we're all used to oh wait you know the
the html's reflecting boom xss you know
game over but but um because you kind of
G grew as a hacker in this highly cspd
environment there's always that extra
step for you and it forced you to adapt
and these adaptations look like these
script gadgets and these you know sort
of far out ways to get around
CSP and and you kind of you can see that
they are also like shared between in
gitlab you can see even the
non-disclosed reports you can often see
them in their like issue tracker later
uh and you can see like these so I in
the beginning I used some of VX uh like
CSP bypasses and then I found some of my
own and then I have also seen like other
people use mine and you get like proud
like yeah way to go
like that's great and now they they
actually like just a couple of weeks ago
they they killed one of the absolutely
the best ones that was like because what
you want at you want something that also
can pass Dom purify right and still work
as a a script Gadget after do purify and
they had like this one that I know like
a lot of people have used it like it's I
think that vax found it like three years
ago and they have never the details come
on let's go it was just like like a
quite same kind of functionality like
you you put um an they think at least
like in the code they thought that they
were targeting a form so they were
looking for
forms uh and that a form that had like
one class and classes are like yeah you
can put that through Dum purify itself
wow I thought it was going to be a data
attribute I'm not going to lie but it
was a class okay interesting yeah it was
a class so this was like a custom code
that looked for this class on the form
they called it but you could actually
put this class on anything but then it
looked for an uh an input element in
this form so the the input element
actually needed to be an input element
but the form could be anything can you
can get those through D purify input
elements are fine and forms as well uh
by default but gitlab is actually
stripping forms but so that was the good
part about this gadget because you it
didn't have to be a form it could be a
div or whatever that's awesome uh and
then it would look at this input element
and for some reason it would take like
the title which is also fine through D
purify and do some sort of like
replacement putting it in the Dom like
whatever you put there so then you could
add like a some something that popped
and it would also then be valid because
it was coming through with like the nons
through the CSP right and like
inheriting doesn't that need to be like
um it's not in some cases it's unsafe
Val but like strict dynamic or something
like that strict Dynamic yeah
okay their CSP has Dynamic okay yeah so
they have nons and the strict Dynamic so
it's fine to add stuff with like a
script Gadget that then adds a script to
the page wow dude that's that's awesome
and these these gadgets are are so
complex and actually I've got a a
situation I don't know um I don't know
did did mon reached out to you recently
with a uh a CSP bypass that he needs uh
on a very highly uh cspd environment or
no I don't think so okay because I've
been banging my head up against this for
a little so after this episode I I you
know I'm gonna I'm gonna show that to
you and see if we can get it get a
bypass but um yeah okay so that that
makes a lot of sense you're let me just
but it's also like it also it takes a
lot of time so it's not really something
you can do if you're just like skimming
through programs like jumping around
like finding one of these so when I I
found some of my own where I could just
like inject this like one click stuff
and I got it through Dome purify then I
know that if I can just find like one
because you could have like an injection
that is like full but then you can also
have these ones that are actually
sanitized but if you can still so those
are like easier to find because they
make that mistake more often than just
getting by so so so with these like H
how do we identify these are you are you
literally just like repping through the
code looking for any sort of like um dot
whatever like clearly a class CS CSS
selector like an ID CSS selector that's
put into place and and then trying to
figure out if they're binding any
functions to these sort of classes
existing or is it just reading through
the whole thing and like what how are
you identifying these is there some
trick to this
or no I've been doing it like uh all the
different ways like uh putting a break
point at the beginning of the the
JavaScript just to see if it adds
something uh but then also just like
looking at all the places where it's
actually using like C CSS selectors to
get elements uh and to see if and for
for yeah usually they have some sort of
like main functionality that's kind of
like
kickstarts uh whatever all the other js
on the page is going to do and you can
kind of see there if they're like trying
to uh initialize ini this reminds me of
a bug that I found that is of course
hacker one my two weeks is up right now
and middle of this pod so now I've got
to like it's always on Mondays somehow
it's always in the middle of the Pod
when I'm trying to like get into my bugs
to like talk about something but the
only thing I've ever found that is
remotely similar to this is essentially
what you just mentioned which was um
hijacking selectors um for for your your
purposes so I remember in this one
scenario I believe it was a waft based
scenario um where I I I could only get
through like on click or something
something like that and it was and it
was on an element that you couldn't
click on or something and I was able to
like name it a specific ID and add a
specific ID to the element and then
later down it would say like click this
ID like this ID or whatever do click and
it would hijack it and pop the xss and I
was like I am alleged you know like and
then you know Johan rolls up in here
with like this 16 step chain um no so
just just to just to summarize this for
the listeners as well um
um like I mentioned before this is a
really great example of how a hacker
adapts in in a different environment
right um most of us like mentioned
before are not really exposed to hyper
CSP environments and as we continue to
um move that direction in the industry
where CSP becomes more widely accepted
and more um you know just as time passes
and it gets a part of everything as
default um we're going to have to adapt
in this way and so it's really helpful
for us to look at examples like y on and
how he's adapted already over time to um
bypass these because we're going to be
doing a lot of Gadget searching like
this in the future so I'm going to go
ahead and and start studying up on on
all this and try to be ready for that
shift in the industry and I think it's
really um a great thing for the
community that a lot of your reports uh
are are are disclosed in in on gitlab
and then you know you're doing
interviews like this where we can kind
of talk through the mentality uh because
otherwise trying to get good examp on
how to find these gadgets and that sort
of thing would be would be really
tricky Frick guys every time I hear Yan
talk about that sort of thing it just
blows my mind I I love it I love it all
right let's change gears a little bit
we're gonna this next clip is from
episode 80 uh this was pone to own
versus H1 life hacking event with
sinology c um so really really
appreciate this episode it was a long
one we covered a lot of stuff we tried
to pair it down best we could um but we
what we discussed here was how exactly
to get a debugger attached to Enterprise
software and iot devices and how pivotal
that is to being able to do Dynamic
analysis and I was sort of admitting on
that on the in the clip that you know
that's not something that I've done a
lot of what I've done as far as
enterprise software and even iot device
reversing goes has just been um you know
looking at the code and then trying
stuff but after talking to him about it
uh seeing this sort of thing uh in
action you know seeing a debugger
attached man it's it's freaking good so
got some great tips on how to get it
done let's jump to those now Cena I want
to I want to move over to a topic that
you sort of mentioned before and then uh
something you also have in the notes
saying that a debugger is super
important to you um and I have a little
confession to make here on the Pod I
have not set up a debugger on like an
active debugger on a on a Target that
I've worked on before I've done so much
uh you know white box um you know source
code review that sort of thing but it's
always been me looking at the code me
crafting an exploit me sending it in and
then being like you know why the freck
isn't this working you know and not
having any introspection into it and
when I think about the luxury of having
a debugger I'm like oh man that would
make this process so much easier um so
for for those of us that haven't
actually had um that experience before
can you talk a little bit about what
that adds to you and then how just at a
high level how how difficult it is to
set it up in various environments like a
Java environment or a or a net
environment uh the that's actually a
really good question even I was the same
back in the day I I would like look at
the source code if it was like a web app
and I'd be like okay this is a function
is taking two like input arguments from
the query string or maybe the post body
or whatever or maybe a header I can see
it clearly in this code and then it's
it's I don't know passing it to like a
SQL query without sanitization okay I
understand it I just need to hit the
sone with my per seet or whatever and
provide those arguments and then I will
hit it right
and most of the times that works right
yeah um but at a certain point in time
you you you come across applications
which are far more complicated uh and
then for some reason you're trying to
send those parameters or whatever either
it's a TC it's a TCP server which has
been written in cc++ that you need GDB
to attach to it's a compiled binary or
it's a net Target which you need to
attach D inspite to it or it's like a
Java Target which you need to attach
like its own debugger to it either it's
I don't know like you need can use like
jet brains products or any kind of
product you want to use to to debug to
debug it and then for some reason you're
not hitting that endpoint B is I don't
know you're giving like a 404 or an
unauthorized or whatever if you're doing
only source code review and it's like a
huge application you might
think why doesn't it work should I move
on maybe the code is dead or whatever or
maybe something you don't know that
thing right somebody's inside my brain
that's exactly what I say in my brain
I'm like why isn't this working I could
see the source code like
exactly you say like I'm seeing it like
either see my de compiler disassembler
or whatever I'm seeing it like why isn't
it being hit but when you attach a
debugger to that like to that Target if
it's say like a Java Target you like use
like a many debuggers Java but like I
usually use like jet brains product for
Java targets you you attach to it and
then you understand okay there is a
filter or an Interceptor or a middle ver
which is which is like way way way
before this route gets called and that's
looking for certain header that I'm not
sending it and that's why for example
I'm not reaching this sync reaching this
function or whatever that helps or
sometimes you want to bypass mitigations
uh and you want to keep testing for it
or or fuzz the behavior or whatever when
you attach a debugger you can in most of
these in most of these uh debuggers you
can start uh writing Expressions right
you can write Java code or net code uh
or like Peck into the memory or change
stuff and then call a function again and
again and again uh and then that kind of
like speeds up your analysis and your
understanding uh
exactly and which is which is perfect
I've I've actually started with
debuggers
uh like with like GDB I was just mostly
debugging like low level stuff just like
picking to the memory not no extension
no Jeff no pawn pawn dvg or Pawn bag
whatever you want to call it no win dvg
or win bag whatever uh none of those I
was just like using like pure like
classic GDB for embedded exploitation
most of that and then I've and then I
was just as I was like doing more like
web app and like net Java I was like
setting up PHP debuggers net debuggers
Java debuggers and all of that and then
setting up a debugger helps a lot it is
painful sometimes and that and people
choose to move on I have I have chose to
move on sometimes but as I grew I've
learned to don't move on and whatever it
takes just have it set up I kid you not
uh in some of the pwn toon targets that
we worked on there were some like exotic
architectures that they don't have they
don't have it's called an TOS like a
real time operating system so it's not
like a Linux or whatever that you can
get a shell and then you you can upload
a debugger or whatever right it's a
real- Time operating system and you need
to when you want to debug stuff you got
to like open up the device and like
attack some attack some sort of like a
physical device and all of that and just
like it's pretty pretty painful and then
when you go through that you're like
okay that takes like 10 hours how long
it's going to take me to like set up
this Java debugger okay 1 Hour 2 hour
let's let's just do it right it it works
so so okay I'm sold I'm sold you you
sold me on the debugger thing that's
great so so that but the next thing is
kind of what I want to ask about is is
like how does this work with various
targets right because you're attacking
these iot devices you know you don't
have access to the firmware specifically
you know you don't necessarily have
access to this um you know Docker
container of the operating system or
anything like that um and you want to
get one of these things set up uh how do
how do you get that set up and then also
you know in in a scenario where you're
dealing with like a net application or
whatever that has like um you know its
own Docker image or something like that
uh how are you how are you reaching into
that Docker image and setting up this
debugger um versus like something in in
the iot world where you've got like a
physical device that you don't have an
image
for uh yeah uh okay I think uh I think I
understand the question uh please please
try to jump in if if it was the right
answer or if if you felt like this is
not the answer to your question uh most
of the time I don't know if it's like a
Java Target if it's on a Windows or a
Linux uh you need to understand how the
Java Java process is being started and
then you can like provide arguments to
that to that command that's starting the
Java process and then when you provide
arguments to it you can you can enable
like Java debug wire protocol like jdw
or like other stuff to to enable
debugging which exposes a de debugging
service that you can
connect to with your debugger most
debuggers allow remote debugging so
that's what Java so so for Java let me
just let me just Echo this back to you
so I can make sure that I understand it
yeah you know for Java let's say we've
got a Docker container it it spins up
this Java app or whatever with the jar
file you find whatever like Dosh file or
whatever that's being run that triggers
that Java command you know Java djar
whatever right and then you you modify
that file usually and and you say Okay
um now I'm going to turn on debugging
and then maybe you got to open the port
and in dock or whatever and then and
then you can connect to that debugging
Port uh via your debugger and it will
allow you to just jump right in and
control that that flow of the
application yeah exactly uh yeah um you
got it right you have this Docker image
you will try to get a shell on the
docker image modified in some sort of a
way to to enable like some sort of
arguments to the to the to the to the
Java starter command or whatever Bas
script or whatever it is in order to
allow to enable debugging that's what
Java you usually that's the trick right
there are some special cases too but
usually that's the way to do it as far
as my knowledge goes um can you hear me
right yes yeah absolutely so so so for
for like something like net um you know
I imagine it's a little different are
you like loading up a A dll or something
like that or or how are you addressing
that yeah so with net you just like uh
you have different kind of debuggers but
like with with DN SP usually what
happens is is use DN spy to dnp has like
a debugger debugger feature you can you
can attach to processes or launch a
process when you launch a process you
can start immediately debugging from the
program start when you attach to a
process you attach to its current state
whatever it is at the time that you're
attaching to um attaching to it and then
you you attach to it and then you can
start debugging but sometimes when you
start start debugging that Target
process in net you start seeing okay my
break points are not even hit so you
need to do that op the op imization
trick that I told you about that you
just place an ini file next to it with
with some sort of value and then you
just restart the process and then you
attach it again um there are some
special cases too but these are the
usual things that happen with iot stuff
like embedded stuff most of most of the
times if it's if it's a device which is
like Linux based has like an operating
system or whatever um you you want to
like push GDB to the device so you have
like a a statically compiled GDB client
or a GDB server push it to the device
you upload it in some sort of a
way taking considering you already
gained a shell on the device because
with iot stuff when you get the device
first you need to acquire initial shell
on the device um so let me ask that
process really quickly so so yeah um I
also want to go back to the net thing
for a second because I I would like to
ask about um remot debugging with net
because in in the scenario that you that
you had um you know we're we're in the
same environment we can just attach to
the process or whatever but if we're
doing like let's say we're running this
unet application in like a you know a
different environment is there some way
to connect from like a from like a
remote context for that as far as I know
this this is as far as my knowledge goes
I don't know if it's possible to debug
it net process remotely with Java it
exposes a port that you can connect to
it
remotely uh so basically it runs a
lessener but with net as far as I know
dnp attaches to the process and uses
Windows debugging apis and Ms cor which
is Microsoft like Microsoft library for
do like CLR the common language run time
these are like do specific Technologies
and engines and uses those to debug into
that process to attach to that process
to debug it um but I don't I haven't
heard about somebody debugging a doet
process remotely yeah that makes sense
okay so so moving moving to the iot side
then when you're approaching this
Hardware Target for like an event or
whatever obviously you got to get this
initial shell to get you know your your
debugger set up and on it right so um I
feel like there's only two approaches to
this there's like Hardware hacking
techniques right where you've got your
Ur you've got your JTAG you've got um
you know glitching related stuff that
sort of thing um or you got to go
blackbox and you gotta you know you
gotta try to pop it without actually uh
you know having the source code or
whatever I guess there's one third
option as well which is like if you can
get your hand on the firm whereare then
you can sort of be white box but still
not have a debugger um what is your
go-to flow with that and how do you
address all of these three
possibilities yeah that's a great
question uh so in order to like start
researching like a iot device uh
basically first you need to like get the
device after you got the device you want
to interface with the device right you
want to get a shell on it assuming it's
a Linux based system not some sort of
Arts or whatever and then you can use
like some sort of like a uart JTAG
whatever to interface with the device
once you do interface with the device if
it has like some sort of a console you
try to like usually after the console
you have you have unlimited shell like
you have like a root shell or whatever
and you want to buy you want to get
around it basically what I'm what I'm
answering is the usual answer right it
there can be a there can be different
scenarios special cases as well which
happen often uh but um in order to
bypass that kind of like a console
either you guess the password or you can
guess the password or whatever sometimes
the password has been publ by someone
else or whatever it's like a maybe like
a roote 123 or a wend name or whatever
and then if you can't get around it then
you can like use glitching sometimes
glitching helps almost all the time
glitching Works glitch glitching is
super powerful if you master it like sky
is the limit and then you can like use
like glitching to get around that
protected shell um if you do that's one
way sometimes the firmware is available
on the vendor website you can just get
the firmware back to the firmware and
install the firmware on the device and
just get a shell that's it right
sometimes it can happen uh sometimes you
just got to like Yol it and then you're
like okay I've I've I just take the chip
off and then just read the chip and then
write to the chip back door the frame
whatever repack it repack it and then
just put the put the chip back but you
need to like know dis like soldering dis
soering like all that um and sometimes
the chip on the device is not like a
like a like a like a simple normal flash
chip or whatever it's like a em or a BGA
which you usually see them in phones so
when you like dis it or like take it out
um you you need to know how to do
reballing which not any can do right
exactly you got to have like steady
hands and like do a clean job uh
sometimes there is some sort of wiggle
room for you to like mess up just a bit
you don't need to you don't need to be
perfect in doing it but sometimes it
which I which I've did actually for for
Ponto 2024 Pon in Japan I I had to there
we were targeting these infotainment
systems uh which are like infotainment
for cars and then most of the times you
couldn't actually find like you had to
like desolder it at least for me like
for a lot of them I had to desolder them
and then uh the device is so expensive
like I don't know two grand three grand
four grand you can just buy two or
whatever uh so you need to like desolder
it and you need to do no reballing to
put the chip chip back and then to to to
use your shell or whatever to go on the
device and so working on it but sky is
the limit as I said sometimes and then
maybe maybe maybe sometimes even you
don't need to make it more difficult
maybe sometimes blackbox you can find a
command injection in the application and
it just get a ro shell that's it right
all right next up we've got crushing
client side on any scope with monan bear
episode 81 um this was an amazing
episode there were so many pieces of
this it was really hard to pair it down
but uh Matan is extremely talented at
client side stuff and one of the biggest
pieces of that one of the biggest tools
we use and that is Dev tools and uh he
really drops some great insights on how
to use breakpoints log points
conditional breakpoints and just some uh
some high skill stuff in this one um so
check this one out there are some tricks
like some very quick and dirty tricks
that I like to use while um testing with
Dev tools so if I'm trying
to like modify some piece of code in
order to test something or whatever um I
usually don't want to start um setting
up a match and replace rule for it and
also don't want to um use the override
feature because um it tends to be a
little hard and it messes up yeah that's
been my experience as
well yeah and it's like it has a few
issues because sometimes
um you know the Integrity attribute um
MH yeah so you can have on a script you
can have an Integrity attribute um that
checks the check sum or the hash of the
script you could also have that in like
a CSP or something and if you change it
like change the actual file with um Dev
tools override then it's going to change
the check some of it and app will
misbehave because it's not going to be
valid anymore so what I do is I set a
breakpoint and with Dev to there there's
actually a few different types of break
points which is interesting there's the
regular like blue um breakpoint that
will just break whenever um it gets
executed but there's also um one that's
orange a conditional breakpoint and you
can put just like a statement there or a
piece of code um in the breakpoint when
you sort of edit it and it will execute
that code if that code returns true then
it's going to break there if it returns
false it's not going to break so if I
want to like override something for like
a quick check or something I I set like
a breakpoint there and I edit it and I
just write out the code that I want to
inject there and I do like a semicolon
and the right false at the end so it
doesn't use it as a break point and it's
super quick it's like wow what the heck
that's a genius technique what the heck
mat
why did you tell me about this before
dude because I wanted to save your
reaction for the PO we're farming
content dude that is nuts I thought okay
so I was reading over this and I was
like oh yeah you know conditional
breakpoints that's something that people
need to know about we should definitely
talk about that of course I'm just using
it like a normal human and just setting
conditional break like a crazy person
you're like actually writing scripts
inside conditional breakpoint wow that's
that's a super cool tip you never have
to leave like your environment and it's
way like it removes friction like you
talked about I think maybe last week or
something on the Pod um about removing
friction when you're testing and it's
super valuable for that W trick that's
nuts that is so exciting actually
because you know what I'm often doing is
I'm um I'm using match and replace uh to
actually overwrite parts of the
JavaScript right and and so like what
I'm thinking of a Target that I that I'm
working on
um right now and I I have there's a
JavaScript function that says like oh is
this feature turned on and I'm like okay
well what what if you just always
returned true you know like that would
be really helpful then every feature
would be turned on instead of me having
to like you know match and replace this
whole long list of feature Flags so I do
that but then you're absolutely right
you know sometimes there's Integrity
checks and that sort of
thing for that specific use case I would
still use a match and replace because um
the log points and stuff or the I'm
getting ahead of myself the conditional
break points are only executed um if the
dev tools is open it's the same with um
overrides and stuff so if you just want
to test the app like the features and
stuff um match and replace is the way to
go but if you're looking at the at the
JavaScript and you want to quickly
change some something it's it's way
quicker and way easier to do it with by
misusing a conditional very cool very
cool but I I think it's also important
to shout out the the conditional
breakpoint um actual
functionality which is that you can do a
conditional breakpoint right you can
write a JavaScript statement which will
if it evaluates to true it will trigger
and if it doesn't then it will not
trigger so this is really helpful yeah
definitely what what I sometimes do with
it um when I'm trying to look at like
some message listener um I put like a
breakpoint on the message lener and
sometimes um like usually um you would
get a ton of different uh messages from
like browser extensions or from like the
regular app and stuff so I just like um
put a conditional breakpoint and I will
do like e or whatever the name of the
event variable is do like ASDF or
something and then only if it has um a
truthy ASDF property it will break so
and then in all of my testing uh
messages I includ like ASDF and then you
don't have to keep pressing that like
little play button play button play
button over and over again that's great
man yeah that definitely reduces
friction and increases the efficiency of
your testing which like like we said
before I mean it just has very it has
cascading effects you know it continues
you think it's just a little small thing
I just got to press you know play a
couple times here but it allows your
brain to to not think about that anymore
and yeah and even more importantly um
you will feel less resistance before you
do the accent so if I'm like trying to
test something and I know that I'm going
to um have to press like four or 10
times I'm gonna be less likely to um to
actually do it so that's a great point
it's not only in the moment it's also it
also affects like the way you think
about what you will do yeah so that's
that's a great point because it it
allows you to go further in your testing
because you're not getting tired as
quickly like oh okay you know I've
already tried three things I'm not going
to like go through this flow you know
five more times I'm just going to skip
it versus if if you just have lower
friction you still are able to just go
go go um so that that's that's a great
we have a lot of different points to go
through here so we do we got to keep
moving I'm sorry what's the next one hit
me so I'm going to go through the next
one very quickly um we mentioned regular
break points and conditional break
points there's also what's called log
points so you put in some code there and
it passes that code like it's um a list
of arguments to console.log so if you
put like a string and then a comma and
some variable it will log um the string
and the variable and actually using
commas in h in console.log and stuff is
very useful and what I usually do with
this sort of um breako I have a very
specific use case for it um a lot of the
time the app um the web app is is going
to have some function that's like a
conditional log of something of
something so they will have some like
logging
Library um and they will check like
sometimes they do it with um local
storage or whatever they will check if
debug mode is enabled so instead of
going in and like um checking how the
checking whether debug is enabled and
then overriding it or something I just
set a log point in the function that
logs stuff um and that log point will
just log the arguments of the function
so if they have like a a function called
debug or whatever that's checking
whether debug mode is enabled and if it
is it's G to log something my log point
is just going to log it anyways so then
you get a bit more visibility into
what's going on dude I did not know this
existed and let me tell you so it might
be a new feature because I didn't know
about it to until recently yeah so so I
I've like I'm looking at this and what's
odd about this so so here's how you do
this guys um in the dev tools you know
they they got the little line line you
know row or whatever on the left hand
side I think it's called The Gutter
technically but and you click over there
and it sets a break point right well
don't don't left click right click
instead and you'll see add log Point
here's oh you can right click wait wait
what are you what have you been doing um
I've been clicking on it then clicking
um on the side panel edit condition and
then you can change the um oh and then
the is way more useful oh very
interesting so the reason I never knew
that this existed is what I always do is
I I click to add the breakpoint right
and then I rightclick on the breakpoint
to hit edit breakpoint and then set
conditional breakpoint but actually if
you right click after break Point's
already set it won't show you the option
for a a log Point it'll only show you
the option for break point so instead of
left clicking the first time don't you
have a little drop down there I do I do
but um up at the top yeah I do have that
but I I I never saw that before so what
what I'm going to do now though is
instead of right clicking I'm or left
click I'm going to right click and hit
add log point and that will just add the
log point on there wow I did not even
yeah it's hard to teach me stuff about
Dev tools because I kind of live there
but yeah I just learned a new trick
that's that's crazy man this is this is
um this is super helpful so we can just
do and then you said these this input
here is just essentially console.log at
that specific point in the curve yeah
and it it's not just console.log for a
specific object it like passes a list of
objects so you can put like Comas there
or something a that's great that is
helpful that is super helpful H and then
then I don't have to like I don't have
to do the breakpoint and then go to
console and then type console.log I can
just log that's super helpful man wow um
very
cool all right guys not going to lie
this next episode episode 86 the EXC
correlation between frons and rce is one
of the craziest episodes we've had this
year unfortunately there were a little
bit of production issues with the mic
and the audio quality is not super great
but the content is super great so we
still snagged a little segment uh feel
free to jump through it if you need to I
know that the audio isn't isn't uh
fantastic but um from 's research here
on uh the X correlation ID headers or X
request ID headers uh is just absolutely
amazing and the way that that uh frons
and Matias were able to turn this into
so many rcees and and critical
vulnerabilities and logging
infrastructure is just really
inspirational so um if
you this clip speaks for itself let's
let's go from a you know blank
perspective not knowing the company that
you're targeting you need to like
figured out what type of uh like Heather
it's actually being used for the
correlation okay one one way to look at
it is looking at responses they might
serve you a unique correlation ID just
because you made a request H another one
is like you can see it in in the access
control headers so you can see like okay
we allow these certain headers and one
of them being the the in this case
transaction ID but they could be named
that's typically in those scenarios
where you're dealing with a cross oring
API absolutely yeah uh and so so these
access low headers are perfect for like
understanding what type of headers do
they actually need to work from the
front end side or client side that's
solid yeah yeah uh another one is like
this is the perfect thing like as soon
as you see reflection especially when
you don't have like a validated format
in this case like whatever H this is
like gold okay uh and it it doesn't
necessarily mean that you will hit gold
on every single request it means that
this will follow at some you know if you
find some obscure you're you're doing a
lot of payment things yeah yeah oh yeah
this this is the place uh because there
will be SSH Keys signing credit cards
and there it's kind of I've definitely
seen this sort of thing before invert
I'm not sure if we're going to release
this on audio whether we're just going
to do it on YouTube since there's visual
comp but um the service transaction ID
uh that he has included here on the
request side right as a as an HTP header
is also being reflected in the response
with the exact text so there's no uid
validation there's nothing like that and
this gives you a lot of flexibility
absolutely absolutely and this this this
tells me that this has gone you know in
the back end and behaved as this is our
request ID and we will keep this request
ID and we will also reflect it back to
you um yeah I know sh I've seen this
I've seen this many times course no what
so what I did is I start first I removed
the existing one and then I just put in
you know a lot of [__] characters but we
don't know where we're going to end up
right we don't know what context we
could be in SQL we could be in F system
we could be in you know a command we
could be in you know whatever we don't
know event Json what whatever so we need
multiple tactics we need to figure be
smart when the fussing in the fussing so
we can figure out some parts at least uh
and one one way is trigger errors
basically like you put in a lot of you
know crazy characters all over the place
uh and then uh are you just doing like
an asky fuzz list like I have like all
of the asky characters Ur encoded and
then I'll app like a URL or I do I yeah
basically you do these D you literally
just type in no no no I do I do like
single quote double quote percentage
sign like all of these things where if
that one like a percentage sign for
example if that one triggers an eror it
could be two things it could be like
Sprint the or it could be a URL yeah
yeah those those are basically and for
example if an person breaks could be an
XML context there could be also your um
and similar things with like dollar sign
parenthesis or or curly braces then then
then you're this is this is one of the
takeaways for me from this event just
from some the life hacking stuff in
Vegas was like I need to do more fuzzing
like this and an identification of what
data is being passed through what
context because there were a couple
freaking bugs like this this time that
were just literally straight up back to
command injection and I was like oh W no
but figure out the context is like what
it's like strugg number so what I tend
to do is like I tend to put this in the
request IDE and then I go on and do
manual testing about you know API paths
I always make sure that verp has it
inside you know keeping it there that's
why you had it IM matl okay great so
then then I can this can happen so I can
I can work for an hour or two hours or
whatever and then I go back and like I
had a 5 00 what what what is the 500 why
did that happen why are you doing this
to me man this is this is of course this
is what you got to do of course and then
this is the fun part because there might
be add like logging specific to some of
these
end yeah I mean I get excited by this
because like I have I have not you know
made this at all like this is this is
this is we talked about before about
like I'm talking about things that I got
bored with so then I presented got that
yeah but the funny part is that like you
could talk about I'm leaving the crumbs
but this is like [__] huge go [__]
pie on me this
just so it would actually be interesting
Sor let you continue but it interesting
also to have sort of like an um I'm
thinking like an autorized sort of
approach here where you have Auto
repeating every one of the requests
differentiate a differential between the
the status codes then you know that that
was caused by absolutely really
absolutely uh and like of course there's
going to be false positives one of them
like gcp for example not all over the
place I guess but most of the time on
Google platform or Cloud platform they
actually validate what you send in just
just a pattern U making sure that it's
like a uu ID strong Rex matching man it
it solves a lot of problems for sure H
another one is like I've seen this a lot
like they actually made a border so the
request ID is created on the first you
know load B whatever and then internally
you can it can be you know sent over and
stuff but on the first kind of you know
entry points no h so that is also common
H those are kind of false positives well
but that's the interesting part so let's
say you have as I showed you here like
you have a bunch and then that one says
no right and then that is still
interesting because then you know that
there's another system not allowing that
thing to be happening so it's still it's
still these are still like super
interesting yeah okay we had no idea
what we were doing at first it was just
breaking and we were like where are we
we're probably in a path or whatever and
but then we kind of you know let's let's
let's just go through what we found
because these are fun let's get okay
first path TR
arbitary and this one I love this one so
yeah yeah continue goe go ahead so hold
idea here there was if you sent request
ID 1 2 3 4 for blah blah blah it will
write it to trace data in the temp
file important part it would contain
itself so the request ID was also the
file path also inside the Json that was
written okay oh great so you've got
you've got control of the path and some
of the content exactly it was the same
it was the
same or like it was a bunch of metrics
in it but the request ID that you sent
in also but path rers basically wrote if
you did like temp data slash and back to
Temp data it would it would write the
Pomers obviously it just took the value
and wrote it and did you just force this
or um or did you have access errors we
had access to errors okay so what we
could do is like we could go down
outside of the temp folder into the web
folder put the PHP code as the
fin 100% fine uh it will then write to
trace data in TMV do the pass reverse uh
we which basically meant that inside
this PHP file you would have the P
Traverse but you would have the PHP code
meaning we when you went to this actual
URL with the T you actually got you got
to be kidding me it's amaz this is I
can't believe they're dumping everything
into temp like that they afterwards like
a race condition or something they they
they have like workers that dump this
data into the temp and then they have
something picking it up from the temp
folder and then sending itly okay okay
so they so the the script itself doesn't
need to connect to a loging thing they
just need to dump a file in the yeah so
that's why
soile name too yeah yeah exactly it's
like perfect H another thing we found
was a hro injection okay which is
basically you you provide they will URL
de code the header when they actually
did something with it so we had like a
client side request added our request ID
it went into an API proxy we injected a
header there because the URL the code of
the head and then the backet service
basically so in this case we're supposed
to see account 1 2 3 just because the
request ID was above uh it will always
take the first header with that name if
you get two of them so then you can
inject another account and then you're
getting their day instead that's nuts um
did you try like uh request splitting
there I guess uh it's kind of like
response spitting but yeah did did you
try like smuggling in another request
because I feel like you could almost do
um you can actually absolutely do this
but no because you you just got I mean
you got so yeah exactly but you're 100%
right the the the thing we could yeah we
could probably go for it seriously get
that Target afterwards absolutely
another one was Java so
s made like one yeah made a per awesome
Tweet back in like like four years ago
and basically he says that like if you
have 010 d u in Java sometimes that will
actually turn into you know z0 d0 a um
and or or 01 ZD turns into 0000 z d h
which basically means that you can send
in c48 c48 a and it will be a new line
pared by J Java dude I I I've seen this
also this came in handy really recently
with um with a JavaScript attack that I
was doing because there's a similar
weird uh Unicode sequence in in
JavaScript it's a percent or it's a
Unicode Cod Point 2028 that just drop a
new line so I love separator or
something what is it is it paragraph
separator yeah something like that yeah
yeah and uh I love that these work in
all these languages we need to create
like a list of these depending on the
context there's a lot of weird there's a
lot of them yeah and he he gives some
other examples I yeah there right there
yeah oh yeah job it as well it's awesome
um another thing is playing
where did you where where are you
finding all
these my
gosh people are doing shanky stuff with
yeah I know I know I love it are you
kid
what yeah dude this is like it's amazing
oh my gosh this is like that that uh
Ruby thing that happened a couple years
ago with the user agent where you could
just literally put a command injection
payload
this was this was by way so I'm not
taking because I'm like who no no no no
freaking way dude that's insane
yeah all righty y'all maybe I'm a little
biased but this next clip hacker wife
Mariah Gardner on bug Bounty mentality
and relationships episode 87 I think
it's pretty great maybe it's because
it's Mariah I don't know but I kind of I
picked this one I'm not going to lie I
picked this one because I think it's
amazing that Mariah after seven years of
marriage has absorbed so much
information about hacking that she will
come on a podcast and talk about it uh
in front of thousands and thousands of
people and this was one of our top
episodes of this year Mariah um was
seemed to be pretty popular with the
crowd so I appreciate all y'all's
support um and I hope you enjoy this
segment of my sweet wife trying to
answer technical questions about Buck
Bounty I think you'll do great I think
you'll do great so let's go ahead and
start it out
um first question what are are the two
primary HTTP proxy softwares oh my gosh
okay HTP proxy softwares so burp and
kaido burp and kaida that's right
correct ding ding ding one point Mariah
easy that's not even a technical
question yeah yeah okay they're coming
don't worry don't worry um H I'm not
going to go down the list in in order uh
what are the happy bug Bounty report
States like what what are the on on
hacker one is happy an acronym no no no
no no no no it's not an acronym
what what are the what are the states of
a report on hacker one that uh like
triage is that what you're talking about
yeah triaged is one what what are some
of the other ones do you know any of the
other ones triaged
only uh got a dupe that's not a happy
State happy one just that good ones yeah
can you give me any Tri and paid like
triage and paid paid is not a state okay
so resolved is the state resolved there
you go very nice Mariah um the the other
one is pending program review that's
like the program needs to go so it's
been triaged by the company and by
hacker one and then the company needs to
go and and review it pending program
review right I was trying to be more
like program agnostic oh okay one's not
the only one that like tries that's true
that's true yeah you're right um okay so
what about the sad bug Bounty States you
said one of them D for sure uh what's
the one the not applicable one not
applicable is it applicable is that the
right word not not applicable yet na
yeah um out of scope out of scope yep uh
that's not that's not a state but it is
a a uh you know a delegation they ever
just send you a thumbs down and yeah
there's there's one that starts with an
I that that I think you know I'm sure I
do I didn't hear you say
it inconceivable in
inconceivable that's actually when it's
critical they give you an eye incon
informative informative yeah so like it
sort of worked but it doesn't really do
anything yeah exactly um all right let's
see in your
estimation how much time does it
normally take for a hacker to find a bug
on a new
scope for a hacker to find a bug I'm
sure it it's very it does it does that's
well we won't try to generalize it we'll
say for you in my estimation for you
okay it
takes about a week to
find 15 bugs a week to find 15 bugs so
you spend like three days not finding
any bugs whining about it and around day
four founds like seven he's like oh
never mind and then the rest of the week
he just stop find some study from there
accurate accurate yeah I think I think
that first part with 3 days with no bugs
and then the Title Wave I think that's
very accurate okay
um I'm not sure if I've talked to about
this level of nuance but let me ask you
this okay so you know there's CVSs right
that's how we we rate the
vulnerabilities oh I know the CVSs um
there's a a metric in CVSs called
privilege required okay and the values
for that metric are none low and high
right so if you find a bug on easy on an
application that is self-sign up right
you can go and and sign up nobody has to
approve anything anything like that what
is the value for the privilege required
metric if you have to be if you have to
sign up it should be
low a no privilege no Mariah you have
you have committed the fatal error um
it's none it's none yeah well we like to
think it's none for any of you program
managers listening out there this is not
an endorsement just because she says
that doesn't mean I'm going to accept it
you have to be a user that means it's
isn't that by definition yeah but but
privilege required
so
the don't don't give me that look don't
give me that look the
um the attack starts
from where you know you can Define from
where the attack starts so you could
actually make a wa stop I can explain
this totally fine to anyone else um when
you are creating the steps to reproduce
the the attack you can just say Okay
first step is sign up for an account and
since there's no inhibitor you can just
go through the step make up an email and
right exactly and go through go through
the process sure sure sure um uh and so
it would start with privilege require
none so just check in general if you are
creating yeah yeah but if you're
creating a report in general do you
always get to decide from where the
attack starts like ignore the first half
of this attack this isn't actually the
attack and no no no no no I mean there's
no preconditions is all I'm saying like
it's a precondition related wait don't
look at the first half but like the
attack actually starts here is that like
a normal no no denied moving along you
don't get to talk on this
anymore do not hold this against me bug
Bounty Community I'm just checking I'm
just check I'm trying my best here okay
I'm trying to understand where is this
light coming from that corner is that
corner all right I'm going to adjust
that real quick yo y'all exciting
announcement real quick we are finally
launching the ctbb podcast swag store
yeah that's right the shirts that Joel
and I have been wearing on the Pod for
the past couple months will finally be
available for y'all to purchase at ctbb
doow swag we gave out quite a few of
them at Defcon but if you didn't get
your hands on one or maybe you want some
more then uh definitely check out the
swag store also if you're a critical
thinker on Discord then uh check the
Discord Channel because you'll have a
discount code available for you there or
maybe this is a good opportunity for you
to sign up and become a critical thinker
if you're not already because you'll get
a great discount on the swag um if you
do so all right cool I think that's a
wrap uh anything else I need to tell you
about that I don't think so all right
cool back to the Pod let's
go um okay next one we're getting
technical now okay okay what is an idor
vulnerability an idor is an indirect
object reference yeah indirect idors I
like oh it's not object no secure direct
object oh no okay no that makes more
sense though that was pretty close
though an examp can I do an example of
an example an example of an idore is
when you're on a site right it's got
really bad security so it's got lots of
Ido Y
and it'll say like in the URL or
something it can have like user equals
and then like a number yeah and then you
can if it's has poor security you can
just like change the number like 5
million to like 5 million and one and
then you get a different user I I I can
see that you've heard me explain this
many times I like you have a different o
idor that I really like that wasn't just
like a plain numbers one like a plus one
plus one user integer one yeah and you
did one that was really cool that was um
you figured out how they were creating
user IDs based on timestamps that was a
while ago but I really like that one so
it was I found one very similar at this
last life hacking event actually it's
time stamp from when they like created
their account or something like that a
time stamp from time of creation of
account down to like the millisecond or
something like ridiculous and then you
like figured out you just guessed that
that's how they did it and you figured
it out and it was like a really long
string of numbers and but it was an eyw
this is such a cute explanation of all
this no it's a good explanation very
good no it's very good you just
described a I believe is a uuid V1 um
sandwich attack or idor um so that's the
sandwich attack that's what it was I
should have remembered yeah your your
specialty
um okay uh let me see what else we got
here
um what I kind of already covered this
but what is CVSs do you know what CVSs
is let me see if I can you don't have to
give me the acronym no I kind of want to
know the acronym because CVS is like the
scoring system of whether or not
something is you know from informative
to critical and I'm actually going to
look it up I think it's common
vulnerability scoring system yeah it is
scoring system so you get you get half
full half points for that full half oh
thank you for your generosity you're
welcome um so all right cool and then we
got we got another technical one and
then we'll oh and then we'll do a
non-technical one um what is an xss xss
is crossy scripting good good can you
explain what it is not as well as an ey
door ID door is my
favorite um crossy scripting is so
you've got like the page right and you
on the right track youve got a web
page you
can sort of like paste your own Co code
over that web page so if you send
someone a link you can make them
Traverse through your malicious code to
the web page and have like both like a
pack it's like a package
deal that that is that is somewhat
accurate yeah exactly so you've got your
malicious page yeah yeah and then and
then how does the package deal well they
go through your link okay yes exactly
exactly they go through the link on on
our attacker page and then and it's
still like what do it tosite link yes
it's their website's link yes instead of
like bad guy. Rhino raider.com still
like the the good oh my gosh I need to
register that right now I need to put
that DNS entry guy. rat.com that's
perfect that is where I'm going to host
all of my PCS now
on yeah so then so then you're right so
they click our malicious link that was
on our website and then what happens to
their
website sucks up the bad website it
sucks up the bad website they can only
interact with the bad good
website yeah I mean that's pretty
accurate because what what you're doing
is you're running code on their website
right does that make does that is that
what you meant to say but it's not but
it's not you haven't actually changed
the website
that's right it's only in the the
victim's browser right other people
aren't seeing it yeah that's accurate
yeah very good very good very good
sweetheart you you rocked it okay last
one what is a good range for low
medium high and crit
bounties good Bounty range for each
thing
yeah H should be at least 8K what oh my
gosh okay well I you said I answered to
like not pro haacker the other on so I'm
coming Pro haacker you are doing
perfectly um okay so we're talking about
like what is what would I expect to see
not what is like would be good because
like would be good is probably higher in
general yes what is like maybe a a if
you look at a program you're like oh
that's pretty good Bounty table when I
look at my programs what I'm looking for
right is
like at least 1K for lows 1K for lows
okay great like out of the hundreds I
feel like it's pretty good okay yeah um
medium's around 5K I'm pretty sure I've
heard you say okay you're doing you're
doing great you're right on the money at
this point highs I guess I don't it
varies a lot from program to program jum
between a medium and a high right it
does yes so like 8K to 10K High 10K yeah
sure 10K can be some crits too so I'm
sure there's like a there are definitely
programs that pay 10K crits and I I
personally kind of like a really wide
range for crits like 10K does feel like
a crit payout to me but also like 30k
would be awes to 100K crit payouts like
some of these companies should
definitely be paying 100K for yeah
Shopify has I think like 25 or maybe
it's 50 to 200k for crits um and so 50s
they're low never crit you may not ever
get them to pay it because of the way
that their vulnerability rating system
works but um the fact that it does exist
and I I have seen them pay it a couple
times so that's a pretty big range you
so you like the bigger ranges on the
crit I do I'd rather be p as a hacker
right I'd rather be paid out 10K for a
crit than never be paid out 50k for a
crit yeah absolutely right yeah that's
just my personal that's I I agree I
think that's a great um I think that's a
great approach all right so that's all I
had for my questions you did very well I
want to give you a little round of
applause here those were like very very
Gable yeah yeah I think you did well all
right speaking of people I love we've
got my boy Brandon my M close to my
heart um and he's going to be featured
in this next clip 0er to L in 9 months
featuring grep Me episode 91 um in this
one we're talking a lot about itac
Vector ideation and how he really uses
um his checklist and his uh attack VOR
ideation to the checklist and then
coming back to it so that he's not
getting distracted and running around
there like an ADHD hacker um I think
he's really got that methodology down
pat and I think a lot of people um could
really learn from how he approaches that
so hope you guys enjoy this
one I went to Vegas and I attended Ben
har sex talk and he done a talk on
ssrf and the talk was really good had
some workshops in there as well all good
stuff and not that the techniques were
anything new to me but I had the very
very hard
realization of why aren't I looking for
ssrf the talk was on ssrf
and I sat there and I couldn't answer it
and I felt a bit silly because I just
thought there's no reason for me not to
look for this I have experienc
exploiting it in the past in a pentest
context I just never bothered looking
for
it so I took that away and I was all
right okay let's try and find some srf
and then for three weeks solid I think
it was I chain I escalated three SSRS
into RC with Alex Chapman for three
weeks one a week um which was incredible
and all headless browser exploitation
obviously that's Alex's Jam um but yeah
it just occurred to me like if you have
experience or some Competitive Edge
around whether it be a Target or R Class
don't disregard that because that's
knowledge and experience you can very
easily put to use with the right mindset
When approaching a Target that was my
biggest takeaway th this extends to
Industry as well right like if you
before you were a hacker having
experience in whatever industry the the
finan industry the construction industry
you know the pharmaceutical industry
right there are almost certainly bug
bount programs out there that will
utilize those terms or the requirements
of that you know field the specific
knowledge of that field um which is is
really really helpful for you and gives
you a Competitive Edge I that that's
something that that me you know as
somebody who's been forced to look at so
many targets because of live hacking
events like I it became a little bit
less important to me because I'm like
well you know if if if hacker one or bug
crowd or whever is going to just point
me at these targets I I got to be able
to hack it but you know when I'm in my
off time when I'm when I'm not hacking
after these live hacking events you know
working on targets where I have you know
industry specific knowledge uh could be
fun so I'm I'm gonna I'm gonna see man
maybe uh maybe there's some real estate
um some Real Estate websites that I can
go hack or something like that I can
tell you right now I have I can list
some off which are private but you most
definitely have access to them there's a
few I know there's a few huh huh I
hadn't I hadn't really I hadn't really
thought about that um so coming back to
what you said though you mentioned a
checklist and I know that you are very
structured and I don't know that we've
actually talked about this but I know
that you're very structured that you
take really good notes um do you
actually use a vul class checklist or
are you is your checklist mostly like
attack Vector ideation then that goes on
the checklist and then I'm checking
those off one by one yeah so when I'm
approach a Target where I've had
previous experience pen testing and have
like a base grounding on every not every
but most phone classes I use a threat
model approach on targets so I go on the
application sign up unlock everything I
possibly can every single flow go
through everything and then once I have
that context as a normal user I'll start
going through my burp history and
playing around with the app and when I
start peing back the layers I try and
put down every single possible attack
Vector no matter how stupid it might
sound put down the attack Vector whether
that be because the functionality is
sketchy whether they're using a specific
technology whether the architecture
lends itself to that whatever it might
be and my whole aim when I'm going
through this process when I first
approach a Target is to come up with as
many attack vectors as humanly possible
so when I'm then hacking the target I
have a massive list of inspiration I can
actually look at and just get really
creative with and tick off one by one
and the idea is that it is a living
breathing list document which I can
never finish because the more familiar
you get with something the more ideas
you should have that's my premise of why
I do that and how I do it and for me
personally with the way I work and
needing notes just to do any basic
function of life in general um it's been
quite successful and you can pick back
up on a Target you can look at this list
and go okay I didn't really try that
last time but it's on my list and then
you can start going down that route and
I feel like if you are in a part-time
capacity and your time is quite sporadic
and you can't just hit a target for two
three day solid that very much lends
itself towards that it's very very
useful yeah wow I I think this if I had
to to guess obviously there's a lot of
things going for you over the this past
10 months that have worked out well but
if I had to guess I think this is
probably the number one thing that that
has served you well is your your
dedication to attack Vector ideation and
and it's actually it's starting to click
with me a little bit now because I've
heard you talk about this time and time
again again and um I've even put it in
some of these presentations that I've
been doing um at Defcon and just
yesterday for the critical thinkers um
the importance of attack Vector ideation
and how pivotal that is I think it's
probably the most underrated skill in in
bug Bounty um and it seems like you have
a good system for that you you you you
start preloading this list you get this
massive list right and then you you know
you start working on the items and you
allow those you allow your your Crea ity
to trigger and you allow yourself to go
down different paths and then when you
get to a dead end a lot of people that
aren't creating this massive list
they're just getting stuck and they're
saying okay well I'm kind of you know
that didn't pan out I I I'm I'm I don't
know where to go next but but for you
you've got this document where you say
all right I don't know where to go next
back to the next item on the list and
then you you know you start from there
um that's really that's really powerful
dude quick quick someone called the
doctor because this next clip is of Dr
Bowman from the episode a chat with Dr
Bowman Life as a hacker and a doctor
episode 93 and our boy Jonathan dropped
some really helpful tips on uh the
importance of having a process in place
to get at that mobile API space um
because there's a lot of friction to it
sometimes and a lot of hackers shy away
from it because they don't have a
process they haven't even thought about
it and they're just opening up a can of
worms and by the time they they get to
it uh they want to be hacking not
setting up you know emul and stuff like
that um so Jonathan gives you his flow
for how exactly to um get a IOS and
Android uh app environment set up um to
reduce that friction and making sure
you're not missing out some of that
juicy scope that's there so enjoy this
one
y'all so pivoting a little bit you know
you mentioned before that one of the
early things you did ear with um Amazon
was breaking apart the Android mobile
app and kind of diving into that a
little bit understanding how the apis
work to build this this website or
whatever that was going to make you a
millionaire um and and uh and I think
you've you've done a pretty good job as
well just looking like talking to you at
the Live Hack events and seeing the kind
of bugs you're finding of looking at
that peripheral scope of Android and iOS
and I think a lot of people go down the
Android out uh route but not as many
people go down the iOS route um so can
you talk about your methodology uh uh
with iOS apps and how you're you're
approaching that um to attack these
these bigger organizations yeah so it's
really important I think as a big Bor
to have a an iPad that is jailbroken and
to have an Android that you can use to
easily man in the middle because
um if it's too big of a hassle to man in
the middle all those apps you don't do
it or you lose too much time if it's
super easy to do then you for examp in a
Live Hack event you get the new scope
you see okay we've got six apps there we
got some websites okay let's install
those apps right now on my iPad and on
my Android wait for five minutes and
then come back and then just start
trying to man in the middle then and see
what's traffic so my methodology is uh I
got an iPad that I Jail Break with pill
rain pill rain is one of those jailbreak
tools and there's still an iPad
available that you can Jailbreak with
that tool that also updates to some of
the latest IOS versions I think it's the
tablet I 7 so have a good look on the
pill R website and see which models are
still supported and if the model also
supports one of the latest IOS versions
because that's a problem you need to
have Reon versions um but the last time
I checked was three four months ago and
it was still working
well um so that's a thing and I got a
spare uh Android phone uh pixel thing
that are rooted but also uh with Android
you can easily do use uh APK metm APK
man in the middle it's on get up so
sometimes I just patch the AP key and
then I install it but I also think here
it's important to to have those devices
separate from your own device because
otherwise you end up with your personal
phones full with strange ads or yeah
keep up your own uh your own security so
have those different devices there also
really helps to open them up and update
just all those apps and see which up
apps can be updated so you got some
check back from the cage or something
new this is this is really interesting
uh this APK mitm um tool that you
mentioned here I hadn't actually seen
this before I'd seen something similar
with uh called objection which allows
you to patch apks and then hook in uh
via fra scripts and stuff like that but
this actually seems like it's oriented
specifically more towards um like
getting rid of uh Sur pinning and that
sort of thing and it just goes for that
so it's like a one shot let me see if
this works if it does great and then if
not obviously I'm gonna have to go down
the custom route yeah yeah and that's
also sometimes I do so then I go give it
a try with freed or objection and try to
catch it myself there's only one time I
was not able to disable the men in the
middle and that some heavily up fiscated
app from some government somewhere on
this planet that that had if I had to
patch it I had to patch it on system
call level in iOS and my good old friend
cck GPD was hallucinating too much to
help me out there so I got stuck in a
lot of rabbit holes and then I figured
out again I might need to wait for all
people to figure out how to do this
properly most of the time EPK men in the
middle thing works or objection
and then the fun starts then you need to
to use the app and just see what's going
on and is there any hidden
functionality do you need to are you
able to to to get some perks if you are
an artist or if you sell stuff or
whatever you can think get the app
configured in general yeah yeah that
makes sense so that's most of my time I
spend on is understanding how an
application works or where are the edge
cases the the uh I really like what you
said here is get some framework in your
brain to for both excuse me for both
Android and iOS where it reduces
friction to get to the man in the Middle
Point right because a lot of the value
for us as as web hackers is looking at
these apis and what kind of different
apis the mobile app is using as compared
to the the web right um and so if you
have a a system in place okay you know
we download the APK we or on the device
we pull it off with ADB we run you mitm
APK or whatever the name of the thing is
to patch it and then we we send it along
and if it works great if it doesn't fine
you know just having that in place and
not having to think about that whole
thing and the same same flow for iOS um
opens up scope for you when it's easy
and when you when it's not you you can
go a different route or you can choose
to double click in exactly and and and
and and one other important advice is
have two those tablets because one day
one will break and you have a lot of
stress so I got two iPads I got two
pixels and that removes all the stress
to for me that if something is is
bricked because it's all jailbreaks it's
all that's and you try to update them
and then see if if pill rain still works
then you don't want to endure this
moments of Truth No you want to be like
okay I got my backup here it's working
if I break this one I still got my
backup there
so that's also an important lesson I
learned it I imagine that helps as well
for like cross user testing like you
don't have to go log out of the app on
this one and log into it on that one and
like all right now I'm just trying to
use two sessions on one iPad you know
it's like oh geez
exactly on on a on a refurbished iPad
that's all refurbished those those
models so it cost nothing you can buy
them on amazon.com and buy them
Amazon this was not alter by amazon.com
please click my affiliate
below give up your dream Jonathan don't
you're never going to become an Amazon
affiliate oh my gosh Al righty y'all yes
it is still Justin here but this time
I'm wearing my hat why am I wearing my
hat in my new accent you might ask well
that is because of this next episode
being back to the basics we the
fundamentals to 100K a year in bug
Bounty episode 99 where I'm sporting
this nice uh cap uh and that makes me
want to use this accent all right guys I
gave it a shot um I'm sorry for those of
you that are not on YouTube uh and all
of that just sounds crazy but um this
last segment uh this is from episode 99
pretty recent segment and we grabbed six
minutes here um to talk about how
important it is to feel confident going
into a difficult techn technology stack
and realize that the people that built
this technology that came up with this
protocol they're just humans like you
right they're probably not that much
smarter than you yeah they're probably
smarter than you but they're probably
not that much smarter than you where you
can't make up for that with a little bit
of time right at least that's the
perspective that I have um and then Rony
was talking about in this segment as
well the importance of learning a new
technology stack as a skill itself
because you are going to come up against
so many different diverse Technologies
as a hacker so good good good stuff
there hope you guys enjoy this
one and there is something that uh you
are grasping right now that I think a
lot of beginners but I know also a lot
of re expert people in the field that
are trying to get into bugti so that
bugti beginners but already expert in
cyber security is that the ability to
find the good resources in order to help
you exploit on some Vol abilities like
the the question that we get the most in
our DMS is like okay where do I learn
stuff like how I I find the information
and I think this is a huge problem for
us to answer this one because the goal
is not to give the knowledge to someone
it's like to give the ability for them
to find their their own knowledge
because when you are going to to get
like this really weird uh technology
that exists just on Two web servers in
the world you are not going to get a
Google search or anyone on earth that is
going to know it right you need you go
down into the documentation the
technical spec and really understand it
yourself and that's how you ref find the
the the information just trying to yeah
to face uh the the the most technical
and root thing
and if we take your trade your trade the
the web fundamentals where when I'm
trying to teach someone I'm just give
like them the mdn documentation which is
I would say the beginner friendly
version of some RFC uh and then I tell
them like to try to find the same
information in the RFC uh that is more
complete right so when you are learning
HTTP uh it's great to actually learn
what is HTTP what it's built on top of
so TCP uh TCP IP uh how do you reach uh
a domain what is a host what's is an IP
and everything and like go to the root
fundament
because sometimes in those routs there
is like some big vulnerabilities yeah I
mean that's that's the kind of stuff you
see with James Kett all the time is he
he's you know sort of peeling back those
layers and addressing uh the
vulnerabilities at a lower level um yeah
I think that's definitely important I I
think it's difficult to give also
resources like mdn or the RFC or
whatever and say like hey these are the
the you know source of Truth for these
things because at the end of the day
like you said you have to
you have to go and find them you know
and uh and and so yeah absolutely
reading the RFC and the mdn is a really
great resource and and something that
that we should do um but there's also
going to be you know those random little
little forums out there you know where
some do some old Linux gezer you know
that that knows that was there when this
you know obscure protocol protocol was
created and you got to read that too and
so it's a lot of it's a lot of digging
and a lot of like you said you know not
necessarily being being intimidated by
these um these highly technical
documents because at the end of the day
this is what I always tell myself you
know when I'm shaking in my boots in
front of like this you know very scary
Target is like at the end of the day
somebody not that much smarter than me
probably you know wrote this whole thing
right right and you know sure there
there are some like you know Mega genius
people out there that are just you know
leagues above us all but I feel like
given enough time
I can I can uh you know compensate for
the difference you know so um you know
remembering that these people aren't
Gods you know this is not something
beyond my my you know ability to grasp
we just have to put in the time to get
there um so yeah I think and then also
you know on the web fundamentals just
going back to the nuts and bolts of the
web fundamentals I think um it's hard to
know where to draw the line on those
sort of things right like do I need to
know what every single header does you
know do I need to know what every single
object on window you know in the JS
engine of Google you know Chrome
chromium or whatever do I need to know
what all those means and and the answer
is no but it wouldn't hurt you know you
know like you know you can always spend
more time going down that path and
that's one of the reasons why in this
article I I outline or in the Tweet
thread um I outline this ratio of
hacking to learning where in the
beginning you're going to be spending
you know 80% of your time or more on
learning and and and but it's very
important to get that you know 20% 10%
of the time actually hacking so you know
where where things are making a
difference yeah and yeah that that's
actually interesting thing like on like
trying to learn everything like where do
you stop like do you need every other
and I think like you need to learn
enough to be able to manipulate yourself
the data and to be able to find back
where you can uh learn uh the for
instance like a specific header uh you
need to know where in the documentation
you can find it back that's a good point
yeah it's not about learning like having
like the the strong knowledge of of the
IFC it's about trying to understand how
you can read the RC in order to find
back the knowledge right um I think
there there is an Aston quote or at
least many people attribute that to
Einstein are saying like why why would
you search uh something like why would
you know something that that you can
search for right and I think it's true
to some degree like you need to
understand the overall concept like the
abstract of it but what the day you are
going to need to to get you know your
hands dirty you need to find back where
you you you learn this from and in order
to go even deeper in this specific
technology
all righty y'all that's a wrap on the
2024 rollup once again shout out to the
whole team that made it possible really
appreciate it it's been another year
guys another amazing year of critical
thinking book Bounty podcast and I'm
excited for 2025 we got a lot of really
cool stuff in store I'm in a new office
as you can see I got my workout in today
I'm ready to go I'm about to submit my
accountability uh report to the
full-time bug bounty hunters Guild and
get hacking so um I'll see you out there
in the programs well and that's a wrap
on this episode of critical thinking
thanks so much for listening and if you
want more critical thinking content head
over to ctbb Dosh show/ Discord join the
Discord there's lots of great
conversations and chats going on over
there and if you want to support the
show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat channnel
with us we'll see you there
[Music]